<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Kaushikc.Org</title>
    <link href="kaushikc.org/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="kaushikc.org" />
    <id>kaushikc.org/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Kaushik Chakraborty</name>
        <email>feed@kaushikc.org</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2018-06-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>WC 2018: Day 9: When push comes to shove</title>
    <link href="kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day9-when-push-comes-to-shove.html" />
    <id>kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day9-when-push-comes-to-shove.html</id>
    <published>2018-06-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-06-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article class="post">
    <h1>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day9-when-push-comes-to-shove.html">
            WC 2018: Day 9: When push comes to shove
        </a>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day9-when-push-comes-to-shove.html" class="link-perma">
            <span>&#9679</span>
        </a>
    </h1>
    <div class="byline">
    <p class="date">June 23, 2018</p>
    <p class="author"><a href="/tags/sports.html">sports</a>, <a href="/tags/football.html">football</a>, <a href="/tags/world-cup.html">world-cup</a>, <a href="/tags/wc-2018.html">wc-2018</a></p>
</div>
<div class="bodycopy">
    <p>When teams go back to their foundation and play as they are known for, nice things happen. But it only happens during desperate times.</p>
<p><strong>Brazil 2 - Costa Rica 0</strong></p>
<p>For the whole time during the scheduled 90 minutes Brazil played the same boring game that they had suddenly discovered in the first game. And like the first game, there was nothing happening. And then suddenly they remembered their lost style. It was those few instances of unpredictable pass &amp; exquisite leg work which brought back good memories. Well, all those serendipities finally produced the intended outcome. Hope they don’t return to their new found stupidity again.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria 2 - Iceland 0</strong></p>
<p>It was the similar kind of foundational African power play that made Nigeria overpower Icelandic defence with ease. This win might impact Argentina’s qualification chances. But it was a pretty amazing game of football by the mighty Africans.</p>
</div>

</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>WC 2018: Day 8: A Messy Debacle</title>
    <link href="kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day8-messy-debacle.html" />
    <id>kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day8-messy-debacle.html</id>
    <published>2018-06-22T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article class="post">
    <h1>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day8-messy-debacle.html">
            WC 2018: Day 8: A Messy Debacle
        </a>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day8-messy-debacle.html" class="link-perma">
            <span>&#9679</span>
        </a>
    </h1>
    <div class="byline">
    <p class="date">June 22, 2018</p>
    <p class="author"><a href="/tags/sports.html">sports</a>, <a href="/tags/football.html">football</a>, <a href="/tags/world-cup.html">world-cup</a>, <a href="/tags/wc-2018.html">wc-2018</a></p>
</div>
<div class="bodycopy">
    <p>Every World Cup few over-hyped teams underperform. It seems the number of such teams is the most this time.</p>
<p><strong>France 1 - Peru 0</strong></p>
<p>France is through to next round thanks to their second unconvincing win. Many considered them to be the team to watch out for this time. Many proclaimed them to be fast, young &amp; skilful of all the big nations taking part in this World Cup. Alas, they showed none of that in their matches so far. Rather Peru was the dominating party during most of the time in this match. It would be interesting to see how far they can ride on their luck.</p>
<p><strong>Argentina 0 - Croatia 3</strong></p>
<p>Argentina had no such luck favouring them though. It’s appalling to witness the demise of a team with a legend &amp; legendary past. After suffering the first goal, Argentinian coach sent all his young &amp; promising strikers to neutralise the situation. But the Croatian gameplay was astounding. They were aggressive, fast &amp; relentless. They not only made Messi lose his skills with the ball but also his usual calm. It was a pity to see Maradona crumbling in the stands hoping some <em>hand of God</em> might save this Argentinian descent.</p>
</div>

</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>WC 2018: Day 7: Reigning Ronaldo</title>
    <link href="kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day7-reigning-ronaldo.html" />
    <id>kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day7-reigning-ronaldo.html</id>
    <published>2018-06-21T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-06-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article class="post">
    <h1>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day7-reigning-ronaldo.html">
            WC 2018: Day 7: Reigning Ronaldo
        </a>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day7-reigning-ronaldo.html" class="link-perma">
            <span>&#9679</span>
        </a>
    </h1>
    <div class="byline">
    <p class="date">June 21, 2018</p>
    <p class="author"><a href="/tags/sports.html">sports</a>, <a href="/tags/football.html">football</a>, <a href="/tags/world-cup.html">world-cup</a>, <a href="/tags/wc-2018.html">wc-2018</a></p>
</div>
<div class="bodycopy">
    <p><strong>Portugal 1 - Morocco 0</strong></p>
<p>Is this the time for real Ronaldo to stand up and shine like Euro 2016? Or it’s a matter of time till their luck runs out?</p>
<p>They had a similar start back in 2016 when they picked up steam very late. But, Ronaldo’s impact is there both on the ball as well as on his teammates. Although they have serious issues to take care with ball possession, mid-field play and callous defence, an immense amount of uplifting energy flows through his mates as soon as Ronaldo make his run for the ball. We will have to wait to see how long will this living on the edge continue.</p>
</div>

</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>WC 2018: Day 6: African Might</title>
    <link href="kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day6-african-might.html" />
    <id>kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day6-african-might.html</id>
    <published>2018-06-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-06-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article class="post">
    <h1>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day6-african-might.html">
            WC 2018: Day 6: African Might
        </a>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day6-african-might.html" class="link-perma">
            <span>&#9679</span>
        </a>
    </h1>
    <div class="byline">
    <p class="date">June 20, 2018</p>
    <p class="author"><a href="/tags/sports.html">sports</a>, <a href="/tags/football.html">football</a>, <a href="/tags/world-cup.html">world-cup</a>, <a href="/tags/wc-2018.html">wc-2018</a></p>
</div>
<div class="bodycopy">
    <p><strong>Senegal 2 - Poland 1</strong></p>
<p>African teams are always passionate and hard-working which makes them fun to watch. And there will be some lone star in those teams who would play many roles – motivator, leader, and executor. Sadio Mané might not be Didier Drogba but he still infuses a lot of enthusiasm among his teammates. Senegal displayed all that might against Poland. It was refreshing to watch them go on with the same stamina and power in the 90th minute as they had in the beginning. They were skilful in the midfield, had a solid defence &amp; nice strategic gameplay. Some of their issues lie when they enter opponent’s penalty box. Their shot selection, execution and collaboration in there was weak. Also, they need to work on their set-pieces. Mané seemed pale and was playing way back. Maybe coz he was not sure of the kind of support that he gets while playing for Liverpool. Or maybe he was saving his skills for those big matches. I would like to see them in the next round(s).</p>
</div>

</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>WC 2018: Day 5: Belgian rise and English dilemma</title>
    <link href="kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day5-eng-dilemma.html" />
    <id>kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day5-eng-dilemma.html</id>
    <published>2018-06-18T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-06-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article class="post">
    <h1>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day5-eng-dilemma.html">
            WC 2018: Day 5: Belgian rise and English dilemma
        </a>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day5-eng-dilemma.html" class="link-perma">
            <span>&#9679</span>
        </a>
    </h1>
    <div class="byline">
    <p class="date">June 18, 2018</p>
    <p class="author"><a href="/tags/sports.html">sports</a>, <a href="/tags/football.html">football</a>, <a href="/tags/world-cup.html">world-cup</a>, <a href="/tags/wc-2018.html">wc-2018</a></p>
</div>
<div class="bodycopy">
    <p>A day with less drama. Still, England maintained their tradition of displaying careless game-play in the world cups.</p>
<p><strong>Belgium 3 - Panama 0</strong></p>
<p>It was a game between a team of battle-tested individuals against the World Cup debutantes. And it concluded with an expected outcome. But Panama could constrain Belgians in the first half. In the second half, their legs gave up. Belgian game in the second half had glimpses of fine play which is worthy of a notice. Belgians might have a good shot at the crown, unlike their group mate –England</p>
<p><strong>England 2 - Tunisia 1</strong></p>
<p>English struggle in world cup finals continues. They took 91 minutes to score the winning goal. Against a team which struggled to keep the ball to themselves. Even though the English players pushed deep most of the time, their game was unconvincing. It will take a lot than what the English have showcased for a better progress this time.</p>
</div>

</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>WC 2018: Day 4: Day of Shockers</title>
    <link href="kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day4-shockers.html" />
    <id>kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day4-shockers.html</id>
    <published>2018-06-17T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article class="post">
    <h1>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day4-shockers.html">
            WC 2018: Day 4: Day of Shockers
        </a>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day4-shockers.html" class="link-perma">
            <span>&#9679</span>
        </a>
    </h1>
    <div class="byline">
    <p class="date">June 17, 2018</p>
    <p class="author"><a href="/tags/sports.html">sports</a>, <a href="/tags/football.html">football</a>, <a href="/tags/world-cup.html">world-cup</a>, <a href="/tags/wc-2018.html">wc-2018</a></p>
</div>
<div class="bodycopy">
    <p>All matches today resulted against any cat, pig or expert’s predictions. It’s a fine day for football when the team that persevered got to keep the fame. And in all three matches, it was the underdog that shined against the stronger but poor opponent.</p>
<p><strong>Germany 0 - Mexico 1</strong></p>
<p>A stunning match giving this World Cup’s first stunner. It had the highest number of shots on the goal by both teams (Germany of course more than Mexico). And highest number of stupid one-on-one misses by the Mexicans. Mexico gets more score coz of their tactical gameplay. They applied the same counterattacking strategy that the Germans used 4 years back. Mexico lacked individual skills in &amp; around the penalty box. And hence failed to convert all those straightforward one-on-ones. Still, they stood their ground against the German blitzkrieg.</p>
<p><strong>Brazil 1 - Switzerland 1</strong></p>
<p>One could not have missed the Swiss brilliance in this high stakes game. Whether it’s fouling Neymar or testing Brazilian defence. While in the previous game teams played in someone’s penalty boxes. They hovered around midfield for this game. Brazil, after last time’s debacle, has changed their coach &amp; their usual gameplay. As they try to mimic the Europeans. They dragged up the midfield, lost control of the ball with measured short passes. And had a weird defensive attitude. All that was completely opposite to their natural <em>samba</em> way of dancing around the field. Also, it’s high time people stop idolizing Neymar. And start pointing out the frailty both in his game &amp; in his presence on the field. Along with working on his free-kicks Neymar should spend some time in gym. So that he does not behave like stack of boxes crumbling down with a hint of air around. As a devout fan, I am still not convinced that Brazil is ready to wash off last times’ wounds and that hurts.</p>
</div>

</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>WC 18: Day 3: Advent of Technology & Icelandic Wall</title>
    <link href="kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day3-tech-n-wall.html" />
    <id>kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day3-tech-n-wall.html</id>
    <published>2018-06-17T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-06-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article class="post">
    <h1>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day3-tech-n-wall.html">
            WC 18: Day 3: Advent of Technology & Icelandic Wall
        </a>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day3-tech-n-wall.html" class="link-perma">
            <span>&#9679</span>
        </a>
    </h1>
    <div class="byline">
    <p class="date">June 17, 2018</p>
    <p class="author"><a href="/tags/sports.html">sports</a>, <a href="/tags/football.html">football</a>, <a href="/tags/world-cup.html">world-cup</a>, <a href="/tags/wc-2018.html">wc-2018</a></p>
</div>
<div class="bodycopy">
    <p>Somehow I could never appreciate use of unnecessary technology in sports. They diminish the charm of human nature &amp; it’s flaws to produce something highly mechanical, predictable &amp; boring. Cricket is already progressing towards such a future of replacing human umpires with robots. Football has avoided such modern luxuries till now. Not any more.</p>
<p><strong>France 2 - Australia 1</strong></p>
<p>Both goals of France were thanks to the technologies - <em>goal-line</em> &amp; <em>VAR</em> which were the only interesting situations of an otherwise boring match. Australians had a highly defensive strategy against an half-hearted France.</p>
<p><strong>Argentina 1 - Iceland 1</strong></p>
<p>Messi’s folks could not breach the <em>sons</em> of Iceland (pun intended). It’s sad to see Messi giving everything &amp; failing in front of the Icelandish giants. Apart from blocking Argentine attack they could also show huge gaps in Argentine defence. These are exactly the kind of games fans like us tune in to the World Cup finals for.</p>
</div>

</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>WC 2018: Day 2: Last minute surprises</title>
    <link href="kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day2-surprises.html" />
    <id>kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day2-surprises.html</id>
    <published>2018-06-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article class="post">
    <h1>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day2-surprises.html">
            WC 2018: Day 2: Last minute surprises
        </a>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day2-surprises.html" class="link-perma">
            <span>&#9679</span>
        </a>
    </h1>
    <div class="byline">
    <p class="date">June 16, 2018</p>
    <p class="author"><a href="/tags/football.html">football</a>, <a href="/tags/sports.html">sports</a>, <a href="/tags/wc-2018.html">wc-2018</a>, <a href="/tags/world-cup.html">world-cup</a></p>
</div>
<div class="bodycopy">
    <p>As Yogi Bera rightly said</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It ain’t over till it’s over</p>
</blockquote>
<p>All games yesterday had some tricks to offer in their last few minutes.</p>
<p><strong>Uruguay 1 - Egypt 0</strong></p>
<p>It was a game between hard workers &amp; opportunists. Egyptians played hard as Salah watched from the sidelines hoping his team to hold on for few games. They made most of the tough moves against a team who are half-hearted during most of the game till they got their act together around final 5 mins. Suarez was useless and Salah helpless. Hope their fate changes in subsequent matches.</p>
<p><strong>Morocco 0 - Iran 1</strong></p>
<p>An anti-climatic finish to an otherwise fluid game, especially from the Moroccans.</p>
<p><strong>Portugal 3 - Spain 3</strong></p>
<p>A much-hyped game which got overshadowed by one prized individual’s immaculate skills. Ronaldo’s equalising free kick in the dying minutes was what we call in India <em>total paisa wasool</em> (bang for the buck). It was so good that Spanish goalkeeper also paid respect to it by just seeing the beauty swirling inside. Spain dominated most of the game playing passes to each other (what they call as <em>tiki-taka</em>). And Portugal waited for Ronaldo to sprint, kick &amp; bend.</p>
</div>

</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>WC 2018: Day 1: A perfect start</title>
    <link href="kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day1-perfect-start.html" />
    <id>kaushikc.org/posts/wc-2018-day1-perfect-start.html</id>
    <published>2018-06-15T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-06-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article class="post">
    <h1>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day1-perfect-start.html">
            WC 2018: Day 1: A perfect start
        </a>
        
        <a href="/posts/wc-2018-day1-perfect-start.html" class="link-perma">
            <span>&#9679</span>
        </a>
    </h1>
    <div class="byline">
    <p class="date">June 15, 2018</p>
    <p class="author"><a href="/tags/football.html">football</a>, <a href="/tags/sport.html">sport</a>, <a href="/tags/world-cup.html">world-cup</a>, <a href="/tags/wc-2018.html">wc-2018</a></p>
</div>
<div class="bodycopy">
    <p><strong>Russia 5 - Saudi Arabia 0</strong></p>
<p>The mood of this match was as casual as the ones of their leaders watching from behind the glass. Saudis were never interested in the game. They never shot on target during the first half and only a couple in the second. But, the <em>70,000 + 11</em> Ruskies were enjoying the moment. It was a perfect start for the host nation. But they have a long way to go.</p>
</div>

</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>2018 World Cup Journals</title>
    <link href="kaushikc.org/posts/fifa-wc-2018.html" />
    <id>kaushikc.org/posts/fifa-wc-2018.html</id>
    <published>2018-06-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-06-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article class="post">
    <h1>
        
        <a href="/posts/fifa-wc-2018.html">
            2018 World Cup Journals
        </a>
        
        <a href="/posts/fifa-wc-2018.html" class="link-perma">
            <span>&#9679</span>
        </a>
    </h1>
    <div class="byline">
    <p class="date">June 13, 2018</p>
    <p class="author"><a href="/tags/sports.html">sports</a>, <a href="/tags/football.html">football</a>, <a href="/tags/world-cup.html">world-cup</a>, <a href="/tags/wc-2018.html">wc-2018</a></p>
</div>
<div class="bodycopy">
    <p>I’ll be journalling my reactions to the matches starting tomorrow like I did <a href="/tags/wc-2014.html">4 years back</a>. As its happening in Russia this time, most of the matches are during Indian evenings (few of them are late night). Which makes a nice after-work evening setup. But now I’ve got a <a href="/posts/aarohi.html">2-year-old</a> which might make me watch fewer matches than I would want to. Nevertheless, I like to write my feelings every 4 years so I would try to catch one match every day (I hope !).</p>
<p>I have always been a supporter of <em>Seleção</em> and yes I got <a href="/posts/the-desolation-world-cup-first-semifinal.html">disappointed last time</a>. It’s not easy to change your darlings after years of emotional investment. I hope Brazil reach at least till quarters. But it does not matter as I like to write about the <em>beautiful game</em> which is beyond a particular team.</p>
</div>

</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
